Rumor. Scandal. Sex. Fame. Revolution.
Marie Antoinette is a drama, history film directed by Sofia Coppola.
The retelling of France’s iconic but ill-fated queen, Marie Antoinette - from her betrothal and marriage to
Louis XVI at fifteen to her reign as queen at nineteen and ultimately the fall of Versailles.
Marie Antoinette, played by Kirsten Dunst.
Louis XVI, played by Jason Schwartzman.
Ambassador Mercy, played by Steve Coogan.
Comtesse de Noailles, played by Judy Davis.
Louis XV, played by Rip Torn.
Comtesse du Barry, played by Asia Argento.
Marie Antoinette is a 2006 historical drama film written,
directed, and produced by Sofia Coppola.
Based on the 2001 biography Marie Antoinette: The Journey by Antonia Fraser, the film covers
the life of Marie Antoinette, in the years leading to the French Revolution.
The film stars Kirsten Dunst as Marie Antoinette, alongside an ensemble cast, which includes Jason Schwartzman, Judy Davis, Rip Torn,
Rose Byrne, Asia Argento, Molly Shannon, Shirley Henderson, Danny Huston, Steve Coogan, and Jamie Dornan in his film debut.
Marie Antoinette premiered at the 2006 Cannes Film Festival, where it competed for the Palme d'Or and was
theatrically released in North America on October 20, 2006, by Sony Pictures Releasing.
The film received mixed to positive reviews from critics, and did moderately well at box
office, grossing approximately $60.9 million against its $40 million budget.
Marie Antoinette won the Best Costume Design at the 79th Academy Awards.
Despite its initial reception, retrospective reviews have been more
positive, and the film has since garnered a cult following.
The film explores themes of infidelity, arranged marriage,
affectation, french revolution, marie antoinette.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.